So... couldn't help
but notice none of you RSVP'd
to my murder mystery dinner party.
Oh, yeah.
We were meaning to do that.
No, you weren't, because it
was a week ago and nobody came!
So if you want to solve the mystery
of who stabbed Koothrappali
in the back with the weapon of
indifference, it was all of you.
I don't think that qualifies
as a mystery.
We all knew what we were doing.
-We're sorry, Rajesh.
-Maybe we can do it next week.
(LAUGHS)
Whoa, we're not that sorry.
Don't worry, I can take a hint.
No more murder mystery parties.
-Thank you.
-Hallelujah.
Because I've got something
even better planned!
-Come on!
-Just hear me out.
I'm going to make you guys
a scavenger hunt
like they have at MIT.
Oh, I loved those.
I did them every year there.
-We did them at Princeton, too.
-Oh, that's cute.
Like it's a real college.
That's amusing. I was going
to say that about MIT,
but it works for Princeton, too.
Scavenger hunts at Harvard
were really tough.
I always got stuck
on the first challenge.
Trying to find someone
to be on a team with me.
(LAUGHS)
I guess that story's
more sad than funny.
I love scavenger hunts. My friends
and I had them all the time.
Oh, these are a little different.
There's a tradition
at elite universities.
And Princeton.
A tradition of hunts full of puzzles
that rely on logic,
obscure knowledge, science.
Oh, in ours we would just run
around town looking for a store
that would sell us beer.
-So, who's in?
-I think it sounds fun.
-Yeah, me, too.
-I'm in.
-Let's do it.
-I'm sorry.
Are we really doing this
or are we tricking Koothrappali again
like with the dinner party?
(THEME SONG PLAYING)
What's all this?
Oh, everything I could possibly need
to win the scavenger hunt.
The Scavenger Vortex
You really think he's gonna
send us to a bowling alley?
Well, if he does, do you know how
filthy those rental balls are?
They might as well
stand on the corner
and give away free rectal exams.
(AMPLIFIED BANGING)
Ahem.
Okay, everybody.
Who's ready for a...
Oh!
...scavenger hunt?
(ECHOING)
(ELECTRONIC DANCE
MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Somewhere... in the city of Pasadena,
I've hidden a golden coin! (ECHOING)
You will be faced with a total
of ten puzzles! (ECHOING)
Each-- (COUGHS)
Each... each puzzle will lead you
to the location of the next,
the last of which
will lead you to the coin. (ECHOING)
The first team that finds it... wins!
He is a born showman.
Any questions? (ECHOING)
Yes, to be fair, do people who went
to Princeton get a head start?
That's not funny.
Oh, it actually is,
if you get the joke.
It's based on the premise that
Princeton isn't a very good school.
Ha-ha.
Oh, see? Now, he gets it.
Okay, guys, go ahead and divide
yourselves into teams of two.
-Should we just do couples?
-Couples sounds great.
Or we could mix things up.
Maybe pick names out of a hat, whatever.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why don't you just admit you don't
want to be on a team with me.
I just said, "Couples sound great."
Mm-hmm, yeah, you don't
think I'm smart enough.
You think I'm gonna be a liability.
Even though I totally just used
the word "liability" correctly
in a sentence.
Yeah.
No, let's do couples. I want to.
No, no, no. Let's mix things up.
I choose Sheldon,
and we're gonna kick your ass!
Yeah-- really?
The only time I'm ever
picked first for a team
and I'm stuck with the liability?
Stop that.
Penny is not a liability.
Thank you.
Do you want to be on my team?
Maybe we pick names out of a hat.
Hurry up and close the door
so they can't hear us.
Would you stop pouting?
So, you picked my name. Get over it.
Yes, and do you know what
the odds are I'd pick your name?
-No.
-It's not hard: one in five.
Now you know why I'm pouting.
RAJ (OVER RADIO): All right, teams.
Get ready to open your first puzzle.
Go!
Do you see what I did?
The first puzzle is a puzzle!
Oh, my God, how adorable is that?
I wish I had a friend like me.
What are you doing?
You have to start with the edges.
There's no right way, Sheldon.
I already found a few pieces that fit.
Yeah, well, take them apart
and start with the edges.
And stop wasting time.
Wow, you're really good at puzzles.
I did them all the time as a kid.
As my mom used to say,
"When you're doing a puzzle,
it's like having a thousand friends."
She was full
of fun lies like that.
If it makes you feel any better,
my mom's just full of pound cake.
I'm sorry you got stuck with me.
I bet you wanted
to be with Bernadette.
Have you ever played
a game with Bernadette?
-No.
-Have you ever gone
into a steel cage with a wolverine?
(YELLING) Faster, faster, faster!
Do you not know that word?
-It means "more fast"!
-Stop yelling at me.
Hey! You'll know
when I'm yelling at you.
Oh. Oh, it's the comic book store!
All right, come on.
That's where we have to go.
But we haven't finished the puzzle.
Well, it doesn't matter!
We know the answer!
You think you know the answer.
But it could be a trick.
What if when the puzzle's complete,
there's a sign
in the window that says,
"Go to the train store"?
Okay, it's not gonna say that.
Well, I hope you're wrong.
I really want to go to the train store.
It's the comic book store. Let's go!
Come on, numb nuts,
it's the comic book store!
It's the comic book store,
it's the comic book store,
it's the comic book store!
(GROANS)
-It's the comic book store.
-Oh!
-Do you think Penny's mad at me?
-Because you're in the right lane
behind a bus and won't go around it?
I'm sure she finds it charming.
No, because I didn't
want her on my team.
I'm starting to think
she dodged a bullet.
The slowest bullet in the world.
I never realized
you were so competitive.
Yeah, I know.
It's probably because I grew up
with five brothers and sisters
so I had to fight for every--
Oh, my God, you did not
just slow down for a bird!
You know they fly, right?!
I think this is
the first time we've ever
actually been alone together.
Huh, I guess you're right.
Wonder why that is.
Well, off the top of my head,
I'd say we don't have a lot
in common except for the people
we're involved with.
Plus, when we first met,
Penny warned me never
to get into a car alone with you.
Yeah.
You know, I bet you and I have
more in common than we think.
-Such as?
-I don't know.
-Tell me some things you like.
-Uh, let's see.
I like harps,
Little House on the Prairie,
medieval poetry,
medieval literature--
Hey, how about some music?
Great. Sheldon never lets me
listen to music in the car.
He doesn't want to be mistaken
for a gang member.
Find something you like.
Beatles, boring.
Eminem, scary.
Weird Al? How old are you?
-Neil Diamond?
-Yeah, I love Neil Diamond.
I love Neil Diamond.
(SINGING NEIL DIAMOND'S
"SWEET CAROLINE")
Oh, hey, thanks for letting me
use the comic book store
-as part of the scavenger hunt.
-Oh, my pleasure.
Always happy to help out
with fun things
that I wasn't invited
to be a part of.
Oh, congratulations.
You're the first team to arrive.
Yes! It's not a ruse
to make fun of me!
It's a real game and I'm winning it!
Your next puzzle is a riddle.
And who better to give it to you
than The Riddler?
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
How am I faster than you?
I'm in heels and I stopped
to take a phone call.
I have asthma. Back off!
"Riddle me this.
Arrah, Arrah, and gather round,
the work of this hero
is legion-bound.
He multiplies N
by the number of He,
and in this room
the thing you'll see."
-Good riddle, huh?
-Yeah.
So when you guys plan fun activities,
does my name even...
come up, or...?
I invited you to my
murder mystery party.
-No, you didn't.
-Oh.
(GROANS) We're the last ones here,
hurry up!
-It is a marathon, not a sprint.
-People run in a marathon!
Not with a bowling ball
on their back.
Hey, Penny, I just
wanted to say good luck,
and I hope there's no hard feelings.
Hey, Romeo! Repair your relationship
on your own time!
Relax, it's a hard puzzle.
It's gonna take a while to solve.
-"Riddle me this--"
-Got it.
Hey, Princeton, look at that,
Team Community College Night School
is in the lead.
I thought we were
the Lightning Sharks!
Hey, you know what this could mean...
Oh, oh, that's good.
Then this would be...
-That's it.
-To the Neil Mobile!
I knew it, we're gonna lose!
Wait, I got it. I got it!
Congratulations, you got it last.
You're really mean, you know that?
So no one's gonna buy anything.
A-ha! Okay...
Let's see.
"To continue on your quest,
leave no stone unturned."
The next clue must be hidden
under one of these rocks.
Okay.
Sheldon, I've got to ask.
How did you figure out
that it was the geology lab?
Oh, simple.
The Arrah Arrah in the riddle
meant Jan Arrah,
a member of the Legion of
Superheroes known as Element Lad.
And then the word "He,"
it wasn't the masculine pronoun,
but rather, "H-E,"
the abbreviation for helium.
See where I'm going with this?
-Yes.
-Nice try.
Now, Element Lad's ability
is the power to transmute
chemical elements.
Helium has an atomic number of two.
If you multiply that by the
atomic number of "N," nitrogen,
you get 14, which is
the atomic number of...?
I'm just funnin' you, silicon.
And that is the most common element
in the Earth's surface.
So that narrowed it down
to the geology lab
or the chemistry lab.
Wow.
I can drink a beer underwater.
And I'm sure your parents are proud.
Now, finally, the line
"in this room the thing you'll see"
was an obvious reference
to Fantastic Four member The Thing ,
-who's made entirely of--
-Shut up. I solved it!
(GASPS)
Those are map coordinates.
Got 'em. Let's go.
Wait. Don't you want to know
how I figured it out?
No one likes a know-it-all, Penny.
(SINGING NEIL DIAMOND'S
"AMERICA")
Um...
I'm okay with you driving my car,
I'm not okay with you flying my car.
Don't sweat it, my dad's a cop.
He can fix things.
Uh-huh. Like death?
Your kid may be an honor student,
but you're a moron!
Penny's not answering my texts.
Who cares?
Focus on the game.
This stupid game is why
she's mad in the first place.
-I'm telling her I'm quitting.
-No!
Quitting would be the worst thing
for your relationship.
Why?
Because it would make you seem like
something she already thinks you are.
-What does she think I am?
-How do I put this?
She's been known to call you a name
that usually applies to a lady part.
Or a cat.
Or a willow.
I can't believe
she would say that about me.
If you're gonna cry about it,
there's tissues in my purse.
Unless you got some in yours.
Big willow.
(SINGING NEIL DIAMOND'S
"AMERICA")
Okay... another 30 feet.
Okay.
Oh. It's a bowling alley.
Yes. Yes!
(YELLING)
My brain is better than everybody's!
(SINGING NEIL DIAMOND'S
"LOVE ON THE ROCKS")
Call me a lady part.
We'll see about that.
-Can you reach the clue?
-Almost.
Hurry, Sheldon and Penny were right
behind us in the bowling alley.
-Got it!
-Great, climb back up.
Come on!
Yeah, Penny might be onto something.
-To the planetarium!
-Let's go!
-To the tar pits!
There's a Neil Diamond
concert next month!
Let's go!
Three bags, no one's opened 'em.
We're the first ones here!
-It's dirty laundry. You're up.
-Why me?
Because you've been training
for this your whole life.
You live in a pile of dirty laundry.
They're here first.
This is because
you made me slow down
for that blind guy.
-Okay, the clue must be in the bag.
-The clue must be in the bag.
-It's just a bunch of pants.
You know, I'm surprised
you want to copy my answers
since I'm not even smart
enough to be on your team.
Well, why would you want
to be on someone's team
who you like to call a-- I can't
even say it in front of Sheldon.
What are you talking about?
You know exactly
what I'm talking about.
No, she doesn't.
I just made that up.
Why would you do that?
Because you were about to quit like
a big-- Sheldon, cover your ears.
I'm not a child.
I know the word "ninny."
Yeah, well, you should have quit
'cause I'm still gonna beat your ass.
Wish I had a man
like her on my team.
Hey, I am every bit
as much of a man as Penny.
Now, let's do this!
Wait, it's not all pants,
there's one shirt.
-Oh.
-Hey, that's my shirt.
-This one is, too.
-No, no, that's not mine.
-That has a big spot on it.
-Wait. So does this one.
Maybe the spot's the clue.
"Sheldon's spot."
The coin is in your spot!
-Oh, that's clever.
-PENNY: Hurry!
Be there in a minute.
I just have to pre-soak these!
(ALL YELLING)
Stop her, Leonard! Stop her!
-Where the hell's the coin?
-Wasn't the answer Sheldon's spot?
Oh, yes, Leonard. Yes, it was.
-Then where's the coin?
-Yes, exactly.
Where is the coin?
Why don't you look in your pockets?
I slipped them in there
earlier today.
-I don't get it.
-Don't you see?
When we're all having fun together,
we're already winners.
Oh, look. See?
Even I'm a winner.
Are you kidding me?
That is the stupidest thing
I've ever heard.
You suck so hard.
Well, I thought...
Come on, I didn't want anyone
to feel bad at the end of the game.
And some of those puzzles
were really hard
and I didn't know
who was gonna get Penny.
Run.
Okay, okay, that came out wrong,
but you have to admit,
you all had a wonderful time.
Run to India.
I just wanted to do
something beautiful!
Hey, look. I won.
(SINGING NEIL DIAMOND'S
"CHERRY, CHERRY")